## Jean-Pierre Joubert

**ID Nr:** 860506 5053 082

Cell Nr: 079 429 2164

Email: valotype109@gmail.com

Situated: Nicol Street 10 House 7 Modimolle 0150

Date of Birth: 6 May 1986

Gender: Male

Marital Status: Single

**Languages:** Afrikaans and English

Nationality: South-African

Drivers license: Code 8

# Professional Summary

I have been in the Hospitality industry for almost 12 years, I started my Career in England UK at Queens Moat House Hotel Group, where I worked for 1 year. Taking turns in Front and Back of house positions.

I then studied Hospitality Management (3 year Course). Whilst studying full time I waited on Tables at Waterkloof Steak house daily. I also worked at a Belgium Chocolate shop as Chocolatuer and Managed Butterfields Restaurant on weekends.

I have been in Senior Front of House management Positions at Monte Casino at Boston BBQ Restaurant (Biggest Restaurant in Africa) before moving to another Province where I started my General Management life at Safari Lodges at Guesthouses.

I have always enjoyed the Hospitality and Travel Industry. Being in top positions at big established properties I have required a special set of skills concerning the Industry and been exposed to all types of guests from all over the world.

Enjoying travelling I have been to Germany, Italy, France and Holland the Nehterlands and Switzerland.

## **Hobbies**

Off road Travelling. Being in Africa the Adventure bug will eventually bite. I have extensively Traveled to Mozambique, Botswana, Lesotho, Swaziland, Zimbabwe and Zambia with over land Tours and own 4x4 Vehicles.

### Education

Matric NQF level 4 2004, High School Centurion

**Further Education**;

America Hotel and Leisure Association International Diploma in Hospitality Management

## **Qualifications in:**

- Food and Beverage Management
- Hospitality Today
- Food and Beverage Service
- Hospitality Sales and Marketing
- Resort Management
- Supervision in Hospitality Industry
- Housekeeping Management

Currently studying Teaching in English for Business Professionals, applicable to the Hospitality Industry.

## **Experience**

(March 2015 - Current)

General Manager Ezingweni Safari Lodge and Spa

**Duties**; Including but limited to-

• Hotel/Lodge Revamping, (Implementing new systems, staff training, décor, Construction, Marketing, Financial systems aid and creation, Conferencing, website up keep, Government contract achievement).

### **Employer:**

- Ezingweni Safari Lodge (Modimolle - Nylstroom,Bella Bella - Warmbad)

## Personal Trainer at Life Fitness Gym last 2 years (Part Time)

## **Duties**;

- Personal Training
- Diet plans

## (December 2011-Dec 2014)

## **General Manager Waterberg Convention Centre**

General Manager Waterberg Convention Centre. (Includes the following properties – Silver-streams Lodge 5\*, Villa Olien Guesthouse 4\*, Golfers in 5\* and Waterberg Convention Centre 5\*).

## **Duties**;

- Managing 4 properties
- Overseeing all duties of all front and back of house staff duties. (Housekeeping, kitchen, Restaurant, Reception, Reservations, Bar)
- Training all staff in all departments, including Butlers
- Managing all aspects of 3 Restaurants including Menu design
- Government Liaison and contract merchant
- Marketing
- Financial Planning
- Budgeting
- Managing all Accounts
- Managing Vehicle Fleet
- Organizing Transport for Delegates
- Specializing in Client food preferences

## (January 2009 – November 2011)

## General Manager Umklewu Bushveld Lodge

## **Duties**;

- Financial Planning
- · Budgeting
- Conference Co-coordinating
- Game Drive and Excursions Officer
- Overseeing all duties of all front and back of house staff duties.

(Housekeeping, kitchen, Restaurant, Reception, Reservations, Bar)

- · Central reservations
- · Marketing
- Government Liaison and contract merchant

## Safety and Security

January 2006-November 2008) Belgium Chocolate Shoppe Irene

## **Duties**;

• Preparation and design of all shop Chocolates

## **Butterfields Restaurant Centurion Life Style Centre**

#### **Duties:**

- Cash Ups
- Staff Training, including kitchen, Barista and Waiters
- Guest Liaison

## Waiter at Dros Waterkloof

#### **Duties**;

Waiting on Tables

2004 Des - 2005 Des

**Queens Moat House Hotel Shepperton, England** 

## **Duties**;

General front and back of house employment

### **Computer Literacy:**

- Microsoft OS's Windows, 3.1/95/98/200/ME/XP/VISTA/WINDOWS 7/8 AND 10
- Microsoft Office Includes, Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook, Access.
- Internet Browser Internet Explorer, Opera, Firefox, Chrome.
- Pastel Accounting Patel 2009 experience
- Semper Hospitality Bookings System
- Innkeeper Hospitality Bookings System
- Opera Hotel Software Pogram

**References:** Available on request

Ezingweni Safari Lodge Monica Castelyn- 082 568 6575

Waterberg Convention Centre Michiel Laubcher (Nylstene) 014 717 3737

Umklewu Lodge Ockert Fourie - 082698 6328

Monte Casino Boston BBQ Closed.

Availability: Negotiable

I have been in a privileged position to be able to run my own business whilst in full employment.

Business breakdown:

Travel agency/Hospitality Management Services French Restaurant 'Allo Allo' Stationary Shop 'PCP Stationers' Car Wash 'Modi Car wash'

I have unfortunately been forced to close all the companies in 2017 due to economic situations and BEE rates which makes it impossible for me to do Business unless I give 51% of my Companies to a Black Partner.

More Detail can be provided.